{
    "id": "8d0379b1a0644f14ab9a88c50b6fe7ff",
    "title": "Confusing Words Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The dentist recommended an …………………… surgeon.",
            "description": "Oral means having to do with the mouth or speech.",
            "answers": [
                "oral",
                "aural"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Hearing aids help a person to overcome some ……………………….. deficiencies.",
            "description": "Oral means having to do with the mouth or speech. Aural means having to do with the ears or the sense of hearing.",
            "answers": [
                "oral",
                "aural"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The city council passed an ………………………………… against jaywalking.",
            "description": "An ordinance is a municipal law.",
            "answers": [
                "ordinance",
                "ordnance"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The ………………………….. is stored in the armory.",
            "description": "Ordnance means military weapons.",
            "answers": [
                "ordinance",
                "ordnance"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "His …………………………. appearance was calm.",
            "description": "Outward is always correct as an adjective and an adverb. Outwards is correct only as an adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "outward",
                "outwards"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The ship headed ……………………. to deeper water.",
            "description": "Outward is always correct as an adjective and an adverb. Outwards is correct only as an adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "outward",
                "outwards",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She bought two ……………………. of shoes.",
            "description": "The singular form pair refers to only one pair of something.",
            "answers": [
                "pairs",
                "pair"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "................................... fire, don’t panic.",
            "description": "We use in case of before a noun if is used before a clause.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "In case",
                "In case of"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Father aged a lot this …………………………… year.",
            "description": "Past refers to time gone by.",
            "answers": [
                "past",
                "passed"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The car …………………………… the truck at 70 miles an hour.",
            "description": "Passed is the simple past of pass.",
            "answers": [
                "passed",
                "past"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A ………………………… problem is depressing him.",
            "description": "Personal means belonging to a particular person.",
            "answers": [
                "personal",
                "personnel"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The company transferred some of its key …………………….. to Europe.",
            "description": "Personnel means people employed on a job. ",
            "answers": [
                "personnel",
                "personal"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}